Guide to the British authors collection M0121
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- MOORE, GEORGE (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - To [Leon M. Lion], with typescripts, Apr. 21, 1922; TLS, 2 pp.,
  - To [Leon M. Lion], with typed copy., May 1922; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To [Leon M. Lion], with typed copy., May 1922; ALS, 4 pp.,
  - To [Leon M. Lion], with typed copy., May 30, 1922; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From L.M. Lion's secretary, May 31, 1922.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., June 6, 1922; TLS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., June 17, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., June 26, 1922; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., June 30, [1922]; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, with typed copy., July 18, 1922; TL, 1 p.,
  - To [Leon M.] Lion, with typed copy., July 1922; ALS 3 pp.
  - To [Leon M.] Lion, with typed copy., July 1922; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To [Leon M.] Lion, with typed copy., Sept. 5, 1922; ALS, 1 p., (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - To [Leon M.] Lion, with typed copy., Sept. 21, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To [Leon M.] Lion, with typed copy., Sept. 1922; ALS, 4 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Oct. 1922; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Oct. 17, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, Oct. 17, [1922].; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Nov. 3, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, Nov. 4, 1922.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, Nov. 1922.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, Nov. 10, 1922.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Nov. 14, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, Nov. 15, 1922.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Nov. 1922; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Nov. 16, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Nov. 24, 1922; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Nov. 29, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Dec. 1922; TLS, 2 pp., (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., [Dec. 18, 1922]; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Dec. 21, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, Dec. 23, 1922.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, Dec. 25, 1922.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Leon M. Lion, Jan. 3, 1923.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Jan 4, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Jan. 8, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From L.M. Lion, Jan. 11, 1923.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, Jan. 12, 1923.; TL signed by secretary, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Jan. 13, 1923; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From L.M. Lion, Feb. 6, 1923.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, Feb. 6, 1923.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, Feb. 7, 1923.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From L. Faber, Mar. 16, 1923.; TLS, 1 p., (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - To Mr. Lion, Mar. 1923.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Apr. 12, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From L.M. Lion, Apr. 13, 1923.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion with typed copy., Apr.17, 1923; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Apr. 26, 1923; TLS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., Apr. 29, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy, June, 2, 1923; TLS, 2 pp.,
  - To [L.M. Lion], June 5, 1923.; ALS from GM's secretary, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., June 24, 1923; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., June 27, 1923; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From L.M. Lion, with typed copy., June 28, 1923; TL, 1 p,
  - Miscellaneous correspondence: (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - F.M. Atkinson to L.M. Lion, Mar. 15, 1922.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - L.M. Lion to F.M. Atkinson, Mar. 16, [1922].; TL, 1 p.,
  - From Edith Evan, Jan. 7, n.y.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Hannon, undated; AL, 1 p.,
  - From B.L. Richmond, June 20, n.y.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - Molly Tompkins, June 8, 1923.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From unknown, undated; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Some of the Reasons Why `The Coming of Gabrielle' Failed, and typescript., undated; AmsI, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., June 30, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., [6/1923]; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., [6/1923]; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., [6/1923]; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., [6/1923]; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., July 3, 1923; ALS, 1 p., (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - To Mr Lion, with typed copy., July 5, 1923; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From L.M. Lion, July 6, 1923.; TL written by his secretary, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., July 9, 1923; TLS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., July 10, 1923; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., July 10, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., July 12, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From L.M. Lion, with typed copy., July 13, 1923; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. Lion, with typed copy., July 18, 1923; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From L.M. Lion, Feb. 5, 1924.; TL,
  - To [Leon M. Lion], Mar. 22, 1924.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To [Leon M] Lion, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
- MOORE, THOMAS STURGE (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - To unknown, June 24, 1845.; ANS, 1 p.,
    Framed with picture of Thomas Moore. No donor information available.
- MOORE, THOMAS STURGE (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - To Ed Gosse, March 23, 1912.
  - To Dr. Radis, handwritten, Nov. 20, n.y.; LS, 2 pp.,
    Found in copy of Moore's Poems.
  - To unknown, Oct. 25, 1922.; ALS, 1 p.,
- MORLEY, JOHN (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - To Mrs. Cobden-Sanderson, Feb. 28, 1901.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Mrs. Cobden-Sanderson, Feb. 3, 1904.; ALS, 3 pp.,
- MORRIS, WILLIAM (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - To Nicol, July 12, 1890.
  - To Mr. Conrad Thies, P.M., March or May 22, 1887.; APCS, 1 p.,
  - To unknown [George Bainter?], Apr. 4, n.y. [1888]; ALS, 4 pp.,
- MOTTRAM, RALPH HALE (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - To Scott Moncrieff, Oct. 8, 1929.; ALS, 1 p.,
    Found in R.A. Mottram's The Old Man and the Stones
- MURRY, J. MIDDLETON (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - To Mr. Van Patten, with env., Dec. 1, 1932; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To unknown, undated; LS fragment, 1 p.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins (46,564).
- NEW, HERBERT (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Album of letters addressed to Herbert New from (in order of appearance):
  - William Ewart Gladstone (1809-1898, to G. Streetly, and to New., 2 APCS
  - John Morley (1838-1923) - to Mr. Hutton., 2 ALS
  - J. Poyntz Spencer (1835-1905) to unknown., ALS
  - John Wodehouse Kimberley (1826-1902) - to W. Defrin., ALS
  - Joseph Chamberlain (1836-1914) - to unnamed recipient., ALS
  - Justin Huntly McCarthy (1861-1936) - to Alfred Patterson., APC
  - Michael Faraday (1791-1867) - to A. Aikin., ALS
  - J. Stamfeld, to New., 2 ALS
  - H. Stacy Marks, to unknown, undated
  - Sir Charles Wentworth (1843-1911) - to New, undated; ALS
  - Mr. Eve, L addressed to Mr. Eve, signature unclear.
  - John Henry Newman, (1801-1890) - to J. S. Sanford, undated; 4 ALS
  - George R. Sim, to Rev. W.J. Clarke., 2 ALS
  - Henry Irving (1838-1905) - to Clarke., 2 ALS
  - Sir Walter Besant, to [Clarke?], ALS
  - William Michael Rossetti (1829-1919) - to unknown., APC
  - James Martineau (1804-1900) - to Clarke, undated; 4 ALS
  - Edward A. Freeman, (1832-1892) - to unknown, undated; 2 ALS
  - William Ewert Gladstone, to New, undated; ALS
  - Herbert John Gladstone, (1854-1930) - to New, undated; ALS
  - Annie Wood (1847-1933) - to unknown, undated; ALS
  - F. Herschell, to unknown, undated; 2 ALS
  - Robert William Dale (1829-1892) - to New., 2 ALS
  - James Orchard Halliwell-Phillipps, to New, undated; 2 ALS
  - Thomas Woolner (1825-1892) - to Wolf deFries, undated; ALS
  - William Henry Leigh (1824-1905) - to Clarke, undated; ALS
  - Charles Dickens, to Alfred Paterson, Dec. 20, 1894.; ALS
  - Richard LeGallienne, to New, undated; ALS
  - James Paget, to New., ALS
  - Charles Cowden-Clarke, to New, undated; 2 ALS
  - Thomas Hughes, to New., 2 ALS
  - ? Raleigh, to unknown, undated; ALS
  - Sidney Cockrell, to New, undated; ALS
  - Aymer Vallance, to New, undated; 2 ALS
  - Henry Leslie, to J.T. Davies, undated; ALS
  - Frank J. Garrison, to New, undated; 3 ALS
  - P. Bosthwick, to the Mayor of Evesham, undated; ALS
  - Fanny Brough, to Mr. Baily, undated; 2 ALS
  - George Grossmith, to Mr. Coleman, undated; ALS
  - Weedon Grossmith, to Alfred Paterson, undated; ALS
  - Frank Howe, to Alfred Paterson, undated; 2 ALS
  - Edward Davies, to New, undated; ALS
  - T. Bonney to unknown, undated; ALS
  - Selwyn Image, to Alfred Paterson, undated; ALS
  - Sir William Hamo Thorneycroft, to Alfred Paterson, undated; ALS
  - Arthur Charles, to Alfred Paterson, undated; ALS
- NOYES, ALFRED (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - to Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 6/28/44, with envelope., ALS 3 leaves
  - to Mrs. M.C. Sloss, July 29, 1944; ALS 2 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Sept. 9, 1944; ALS 2 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Oct. 21, 1944; ALS 4 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Dec. 11, 1944; ALS 2 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Dec. 12, 1944; ALS 2 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Oct. 6, 1945; ALS 2 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Nov. 5, 1945; ALS 2 pp.
  - to Mrs.M.C. Sloss, Oct. 15, 1949; TLS 2 pp.
    Source: Mrs M.C. Sloss?
  - Book of Poems, Pageant of Empire, by Alfred Noyes. One is handwritten, the others, typed. All contain author's signature. Also contains a signed preface by Sir Charles Oman, by the Duke of Windsor, and three other letters relating to the Pageant of Empire, held at Wembley Stadium, London, in, 1924.; 1 TLS (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Purchased from William Wreden
- O'FLAHERTY, LIAM (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Mermaid, July, 1929.; AMsS, 8 pp.,
    Source: Zeitlin (#1062)
- PARKER, GILBERT (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - To May Lilienthal, May 8, 1902.; PCS (an autograph only),
- PHILLPOTTS, EDEN (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - To Harold Kamp, 8/17/28.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Harold Kamp, Mar. 12, 193?; ALI, 2 pp,
    Source: Lil Gelber.
  - To Gustave Tuck, Apr. 27, 1993.; 2 pp.,
    Found in Nancy Owlett, by Eden Philpotts.
- POWYS, LLEWELYN (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - To Frederick [O' Brien], Cancelled check from O'Brien, June 19, 1930. May 27, 1936.; ALS, 2 pp.,
- PROCTER, ADEL (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - God Our Strength, handwritten MS poem, undated; 3 pp.,
- ROBERTS, CHARLES G.D. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ancestral, Apr. 24, 1893.; TMS (poem), 2 pp.
  - The Quest of the Arbutus, undated; TMs, 1 p.
  - Significance, undated; TMs, 2 pp.,
    Source: Sigurd Russell.
- RUSSELL, BERTRAND (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - To Donald Clyde Rogers, Jan. 28, 1963.; TLS, xerox, 1 p.,
- SCOTT, SIR WALTER (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - To Davis Adams, 1828.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To? Donaldsen, Mar. 1814.; AL, 1 p.,
  - To? Donaldsen, Mar. 24, 1817.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To? Donaldsen, Apr. 12, 1817.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To? Donaldsen, July 22, 1819.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To? Donaldsen, plus typescript., Aug. 3, 1820; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To? Donaldsen, plus typescript., Sept. 17, 1820; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To [Stuart] Donaldsen, Sept. 23, 1820.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Stuart Donaldsen, Aug. 21, 1861.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To the author of Epistles from Scotland and Translations, June 1, 1813.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Aubrey DeVere Hunt, July 12, 1823.; 1 p.,
  - To Alex Keith, Mar. 5, 1814.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Sir William Knighton, Sept. 27, 1813.
- SCOTT, SIR WALTER (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - To unknown, (from Mrs. K.F. Elkins)., undated; framed ALS, 1 p.,
  - To unknown, undated; AN,
- SETON, ERNEST THOMPSON, Autograph (Box 4, Folder 13)
- SHAKESPEARE, WILLIAM
  - Facsimile Mss, handwritten and signed, undated; 2 copies,
    Note: Stored with oversize items in mapcase.
- SHARP, ISAAC (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - To Ida Shelley, with typed copy., 1888; ALS, 1 p.,
- SHARP, WILLIAM (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - To Gray, undated; ALS,
    Found in Life of Robert Browning by Robert Browning.
- SITWELL, EDITH (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - To Mr. Allen, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
  - Invitations, undated; AMs, 6 pp.,
    Purchased from Maggs Brothers Ltd.
- SMEDLEY, EDWARD (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Original journal decribing in detail his wanderings in the north of England and Scotland, the people he met, anecdotes, reflections, original verses, with some small sketches, 1809.; 100 pp.,
- SMITH, ALBERT (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - To unknown, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
    Purchased (price 13-1-1 erased).
- SMITH, GOLDWIN (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - To the Colorado Springs Gazette, May 2, 1902.; TL newsclipping,
- SPENCER, HERBERT (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - To Laurie Magnus, Nov. 18, 1903.; LS, 2 pp.,
- STEPHENS, JAMES (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - To David Magee, n.d.; ANS, xerox, 1 p., 3 copies.
  - Dolores Cadell to David Magee, Feb. 13, 1952.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Evelyn Steele Little to David Magee, Mar. 21, 1955.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Phillip A. Maxwell to David Magee, Jan. 21, 1960.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Phillip A. Maxwell to David Magee, Feb. 11, 1960.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Autograph, Aug. 1909
  - Printed brochures about Stephens and his work, Xeroxed poems, author unidentified, with Stephen's handwritten comments in the margins, n.d. n.d.; 2 poems, 1 page each,
    Source: Magee.
- STEVENS, W.G. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Bourn Hall and the DeLaWarr Family, May 1963.; TMs, 20 pp.,
    Source: Huntingdonshire Record Office.
- STEVENSON, ROBERT LOUIS (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - F. Margaret Isabella Balfour Stevenson to Tom, Jan. 4, 1852.; ALS, 4 pp.,
    Source: K.F. Elkins
  - To Cummy aka Alison Cunningham, (poem) to his nurse, undated; 1 p.,
    Purchased from Zeitlin.
- SWINBURNE, ALGERNON CHARLES (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - To [William Clowes & Sons], Dec. 26, 1875.; ALS, 10 pp.
  - To Wm. Clowes & Sons, ALS, plus 4 pp. of printer's comments., Dec. 30, 1875; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To unknown, Aug. 15, 1905.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - DeMonumentis Epilaphisque, plus typescript., undated; AMs (school essay) 5 pp., (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Limits of Experience, plus typescript., undated; AMs (essay), 5 pp,
    These two mss. are bound together. No donor information available. (Price of $200.00 erased)
  - Mr. Whistler's Lecture on Art, facsimile, undated; AMs, 13 pp., (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Gift of the estate of Leon Liebes.
  - The Masque of Queen Bersabe, undated; AMs, 21 pp., (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Gift of Christian deGuigne.
- THACKERAY, WILLIAM (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - To Fadiman [?], with print of portrait by Samuel Lawrence, n.d., n.d.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - Pencil sketch by Thackeray, several scenes, 1 p.
    - Caricature of Thackeray and Dickens, undated
    - Three prints of portraits of Thackeray, undated
    - Pressed leaves and a list of celebrated people buried at Kensall Green.
      Gift of Hans Barkans
      Some printed materials removed and put in Felton Vertical File.
  - To unknown addressee, framed with drypoint of self-portrait, signed, n.d. n.d.; ANS, 1 p., (Box 5, Folder 11)
- TODD, HENRY JOHN (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - To Robert Lemon, June 16, 1826; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Robert Lemon, July 22, 1826.; ALS, 1 p.,
    Found in Todd's biography of Milton.
- TOMLINSON, H.L. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - To Emmo, June 9, 1922.; ALS (signed Waddon, a nickname), 2 pp.
    Gift of Mrs. K.F. Elkins.
- WARD, MARY AUGUSTA (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - From unknown, Oct. 13, 1913.; ALS, 3 pp.,
    Found in the Coryston Family.
  - Marcella, undated; AMs, p. 28 only,
    Tipped in to Vol. 3 of Ward's Marcella.
  - To the Poppies on the Battlefield of the Somme, Aug. 1917.; AMs (poem), 1 p.,
    Found in Ward's Field's of History.
- WEBB, BEATRICE (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - To Morse Stephens, May 13, 1914.; TLS, 1 p.,
- WEBB, MARY (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - To Mr. O'Grady, undated; ALS, 4 pp.,
  - To Mr. O'Grady, undated; ALS, 4 pp.,
    From the presentation copy of Spring of Joy, purchased from David Magee.
- WEST, REBECCA (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - To Bertrand Russell, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
- WHITE, W. HALE (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - To Mrs. T.J. Cobden-Sanderson, Mar. 8, 1907.; ALS, 1 p.,
- WISE, THOMAS J. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - To Walter Slater, Jan. 21, 1887.; ALS, 1p.,
  - To Walter Slater, Nov. 22, 1887.; ALS, 2 pp.,
    Purchased from Wreden (#3831,3832)
  - Ticket to Shelley Society Lecture, Dec. 14, n.y.
  - Shelley Society pamphlets, One pamplet inscribed by Wise to Walter Slater., 1887.
    Purchased: price of 15.00 erased.
- YORKE, HENRY VINCENT (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Living, undated; AMs, Vol. 1, 141 pp.,
  - Living, undated; AMs Vol. 2, pp. 142-283, (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Living, undated; AMs Vol. 3, pp. 284-385, (Box 6, Folder 2)
- YOUNGE, CHARLOTTE M. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - To John, Dec. 21, 1882.; ALS, 4 pp.,
- ZANGWILL, ISRAEL (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - To Miss Floss, with envelope, July 22, 1924; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Miss Hecht, Sept. 21, 1896.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Louis Hecht, with envelope., Mar. 22, 1899; ALS, 1 p.,